Guilherme Branco Stracini

Dublin, County Dublin, Ireland

guilherme@guilhermebranco.com.br



+971 52 615 1060



linkedin.com/in/guilhermestracini



https://guilherme.stracini.com/

Summary

Software engineer well experienced with C# .NET and Node.JS.

Currently working at OUTsurance (originally from South Africa), which is an insurance company, based in Dublin, Ireland as a senior software engineer, working on an Irish project, using C# .NET 6/7, Azure DevOps, RabbitMQ, Azure Service Bus, Azure Cosmos DB, Terraform and other tools in the Billing & Finance project.

Previously worked in Talabat (part of Delivery Hero), which is a delivery company in MENA, based in Dubai. As a backend engineer, working with C# .NET, AWS (SQS, SNS, Lambda, S3, SSM, EC2), Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Terraform, ArgoCD, CircleCl and other tools on QCommerce tribe, supported by TDD, DDD, SOLID, KISS & DRY.

Two years with a financial background, direct contact with B2B clients, regulatory agencies, other banks, and technical teams to provide the best solution for both sides.

I am excited to contribute my strengths and proficiency in innovation to your team efforts.

As an extroverted and personable communicator with a proven track record in technical writing, my focus on building strong professional relationships has been a valuable asset throughout my career.

Experience (in years):

12+ C# .NET

12+ Javascript

12+ Microsoft SQL Server (SQL)

10+ MySQL (SQL)

8+ Node.JS

7+ .NET Framework

7+ Elastic Search (noSQL)

6+ .NET Core

5+ Redis (noSQL)

4+ AWS (Amazon Web Services)

4+ ReactJS

3+ Azure

3+ RabbitMQ

3+ PostgreSQL (SQL)

3+ Apache Kafka

2+ NextJS

2+ Redux

2+ CosmosDB (noSQL)

Some projects I worked on:

- Insurance platform (billing, collections & payments)
- Food & Grocery delivery Shopping Experience & Order Fulfillment

- Digital wallet development
- Western Union integration/RPA for remittance across countries
- Digital wallet (payments, transfers, remittance, balance, statement, mobile top-up, credit card)
- SPI PIX Brazilian Instant Payments System (Brazil BACEN)
- Open Banking / Open Finance (Brazil BACEN)
- Banking as a Service (BaaS)
- Microservices culture
- Distributed systems using RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka, Azure Service Bus
- Gateway integrations with MaxiPago, Adyen and PayPal, Western Union
- Internet banking project for B2B customers development
- VTEX (e-commerce PaaS), Zendesk (CRM) integration
- Sankhya / SAP (ERPs) management, analysis, integration
- Digital video platforms development
- Subscription learning platform development
- Database management
- Agile methodologies
- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- General web development
- Open Source Software (OSS): C# .NET, PHP, Rust, and JS: https://github.com/guibranco

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

OUTsurance

Apr 2023 - Present (4 months)

OUTsurance, a South African insurance company, working on the Irish front.

Modeling, developing, and building the billing scheduling and payment collection system. Integrating the system with the company's internal systems and connecting to banks, payment gateways, and credit card acquirers in the Irish market

- Develop billing, collections, and payments scheduler system
- Integration with policy administration portal
- Building APIs and services with C# .NET 7, Azure Service Bus, RabbitMQ, and CosmosDB
- Setup infrastructure with IaC using Terraform
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira and Azure DevOps

Software Engineer

talabat

Jan 2022 - Mar 2023 (1 year 3 months)

Working on Grocery Shopping Experience squad (former FAST - Finding and Shopping Team squad)

- Improve search, offers, and shopping experience in the Grocery tribe / QCommerce tribe
- Migration from a monolithic architecture to a microservices architecture
- Building APIs and services with C# (.NET 5/6/7), Amazon SQS, SQL Server, and PostgreSQL
- Configuration of the backend for frontend (BFF) API gateway using KrakenD, Luna, and GoLang
- DDD (Domain Driven Design) and TDD (Test Driven Development) approaches
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum over Jira

Software Engineer

talabat

May 2021 - Dec 2021 (8 months)

Working on the Grocery Fulfillment squad

- Improve the quality of the fulfillment process by working together with all grocery tribe
- Migration from a monolithic architecture to a microservices architecture
- Item heartbeat/grocery catalog availability monitoring, providing pickers to set an item unavailable at the handle & ship process
- Item replacement allowing customers, pickers, and back office to change unavailable items on an order
- Robocalls, automated phone calls with Asterisk integration
- Building APIs and services with C# (.NET 5), Amazon SQS, Amazon SNS, Amazon Lambda, SQL Server, and PostgreSQL
- DDD (Domain Driven Design) approach
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

Senior Software Engineer

Syndigo

Jun 2021 - Nov 2021 (6 months)

(Part-Time / Contract) Working on Customer Experience Hub (CXH) platform

- Integrations with Instacart and BestBuy
- Improve the quality of code, fixing code smells and bugs
- Building APIs and services with C# (.NET Core 3.1/.NET 5), Azure Blob Storage, Azure Service Bus, and SQL Server
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira and Azure DevOps

Senior Software Engineer

FCamara Consulting & Training

May 2021 - Aug 2021 (4 months)

(Part-Time / Contract) Working for FCamara, in the Open Banking / Open Finance project

- Developing IdP (Identity Provider), DCR (Dynamic Client Registration)
- Developing White Label platform
- Integration with Banco Pan
- Building APIs with Node.JS (JavaScript and TypeScript), Azure Cosmos DB, Azure Service Bus
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

Senior Software Engineer

The Bridge Social

Feb 2021 - May 2021 (4 months)

(Part-time / Contract) Working for Grace Kennedy (Jamaica & Caribbean area) client, developing:

- Remittance integration with Western Union
- Digital wallet system

- Building API and Services with C# (.NET Core 3.1 and .NET 5), using CosmosDB, Microsoft Azure Service Bus, Entity Framework Core, Dapper, Application Insights, RPA (Robotic Procedure Automation)
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

https://www.gracekennedy.com/

FARFETCH

Dec 2020 - May 2021 (6 months)

Working on Search & Scouts team:

- Development of improvements in the search services of the platform
- Development solutions using Kafka, Cassandra, C# (.NET Core), Elastic Search
- Working side-by-side with the Data Scientists team providing data and schemes for our project
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

bsz Senior Software Engineer

Banco BS2

Mar 2020 - Jan 2021 (11 months)

Working on the Special Projects team, part of the Financial Services division

- Implementation of PIX/SPI (Brazilian Instantly Payments BACEN)
- Development of APIs and Services using C# .NET Core, Dapper, Entity Framework, and DDD
- Architecture of the CORE PIX and Indirect PIX solutions inside the BS2 Bank
- Development of an accounting system for Indirect PIX partners
- Development of distributed systems using RabbitMQ
- Deploy and develop using Docker containers
- Supporting internal clients in the integration process
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

bsz Middle Software Engineer

Banco BS2

Jul 2019 - Mar 2020 (9 months)

Working on B2B tribe, on API Banking squad

- Development of API banking product (https://devs.bs2.com) BaaS
- Development of open banking project
- Development of APIs using C# .NET Core, Dapper, Entity Framework, and DDD
- Development of distributed systems using RabbitMQ
- Deploy and develop using Docker containers
- Supporting clients in the integration process
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Team Foundation Service (TFS)

Middle Software Engineer

C&A Brasil

Dec 2018 - Jun 2019 (7 months)

Working on the e-commerce team, and on the refund/reversal squad.

- Development of integrations solutions using Zendesk, SAP, Oracle, and other internal systems
- Automation of payment/refund process using Adyen gateway
- Automation of process using C# .NET Core
- Implement Elastic Search and Kibana for logs & metrics in the e-commerce team
- Develop new features and APIs using Node.JS (Express & HAPI)
- Develop a unified library in C# .NET Core to be used internally by all teams, with common & util needs
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

Project Development Coordinator

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Jan 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 years 11 months)

Head of development in IT department. Managing developers' teams, agencies, and associates.

- Development of services and APIs using C# (.NET Framework 4.7/4.8/4.8.1 and .NET Core 2.1)
- Implement SOLID principles
- Implement Apache Kafka and RabbitMQ for distributed systems process
- Implement Elastic Search and Kibana for log & metrics purposes
- Development of an internal search engine using data from Elastic Search (clients, orders, and orders items)
- Deploy, evangelize, and speech of continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD)
- Development of integrations solutions
- Development of RESTful APIs for mobile apps
- Coordinate the development of a CRM system
- DevOps culture
- Agile culture & ceremonies using Scrum and Kanban over Trello and RunRun.lt

Software Development Analyst

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2013 - Dec 2015 (2 years 2 months)

Development of paid subscription platform, integration with services and APIs, and resource management.

- Website development using ASP.NET C# .NET technology and MVC standard
- Web API 2 (C# .NET) web applications for the user data access (via client web application) and restricted access data management of other internal projects
- Application development for product and order integration with the Smart Checkout / VTEX platform (SOAP web service / REST API)
- Payment gateway integration MaxiPago for subscription management
- Management of triggers and procedures in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 database
- Disaster Management / Automated Backup Plans on Microsoft SQL Server and Windows Server
- Automated backup with Amazon Web Service (AWS) S3

IT Analyst

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year)

Develop content platforms, video portals, internal systems, and integrations.

- Development of video portal using C# .NET language and MVC standard
- Development of service integration tool (SOAP web service and REST API) in C# .NET
- Monitoring and management of SQL Server database
- Requirements gathering
- Planning, modeling, implementation, and process documentation ERP (Sankhya)

Information Technology Intern

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2011 - Oct 2012 (1 year)

Main help desk and support.

- Development of emails marketings campaigns (coding, triggering, reports)
- Formatting, maintenance, and installation of micro-computers(Windows and Linux Ubuntu)
- General software installation and configuration
- Development of internal systems in VB.NET
- Development of system (VB.NET) for management of digital PBX (Total IP)
- Development of new features, tools, and bug fixes in existing projects (classic ASP and PHP)

Freelance Software Developer

Guilherme Branco Stracini ME

Jan 2007 - Dec 2021 (15 years)

Acting as an independent consultant for some companies, worked on some projects per contract/deliveries.

- Development of portals and applications using: C# .NET, PHP, Node.JS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize
- One-off jobs, as a freelancer, using C# .NET, PHP, SQL, Node.JS, and Rust
- Consultancy
- Integrations with VTEX (SaaS e-commerce platform) using C# .NET framework
- Integrations with Sankhya (ERP) using C# .NET framework and Microsoft SQL Server
- Integrations with payment gateways
- EBAOH project Products review platform with gamification

Education

Fatec FATEC São Caetano do Sul - Antonio Russo

Systems Analysis and Development Technologist, College - Technologist

Jan 2011 - Dec 2013

Analyses, designs, documents, specifies, tests, implements and maintains computational information systems - 2800 hours - on-site classes.

señac Senac

Computer technician, Informatics

Jan 2008 - Jun 2010

Assemble and maintain microcomputers, install and configure networks and develop systems and websites - 1200 hours, on-site classes.

CN ETEC Professor Camargo Aranha

High School Diploma, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates Jan 2007 - Dec 2009

CNA Idiomas - Unidade Belenzinho - SP

English Course, English Language and Literature, General Jan 2004 - Dec 2009 Language course, 6 years on site classes.

Skills

Jira • Financial Services • Azure Cosmos DB • REST APIs • Test Automation • ASP.NET Core • Test Driven Development • Domain-Driven Design (DDD) • Microsoft SQL Server • C#